GUIDE TO THE AMERICAN ASSOCIATION OF SCHOOL ADMINISTRATORS COLLECTION MS2352
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Operations, 1980-2002; Series 7; 4.5 Linear Feet
  - Forty-Ninth Annual Meeting of the Department of Superintendence, February 24-March 1, 1919; Series 7 (Box 314, Folder 7)
  - Group Picture of Masses of Children 0 Used in "Planning America's School Buildings," AASA School Building Commission, Undated; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 10)
  - Harrisburg, PA, AASA Centennial Celebrations, August 16-17, 1965; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 11)
  - Harrisburg, PA, AASA State Presidents' Conference, August 15-16, 1965; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 12)
  - Historic Sidebars (?) 21st Cont., Undated; Series 7 (Box 220, Folder 4)
  - Hot Springs, AR, AASA Southwest Regional Drive-In Conference of Community School Administrators, April 12-14, 1964; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 13)
  - How Our Investment in Education Pays Off, 1994; Series 7 (Box 220, Folder 5)
  - How Students Have Changed, 1995; Series 7 (Box 220, Folder 6)
  - Hoyle, John, Undated; Series 7 (Box 220, Folder 7)
  - J# 18960 AALS, Undated; Series 7 (Box 220, Folder 8)
  - Keeping Spirits High, 1993; Series 7 (Box 220, Folder 9)
  - Lessons Learned Along the Way, Undated; Series 7 (Box 220, Folder 10)
  - Logos and Signatures, Undated; Series 7 (Box 220, Folder 11)
  - Lois Edinger and Richard Batchelder, July 3, 1964; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 14)
  - Meeting of 1968 AASA Resolutions Committee, September 29-30, 1967; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 15)
  - Meeting of Jury for 1968 AASA Exhibition of School Architecture, November 13-15, 1967; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 16)
  - Miami Beach, Florida, NEA Convention, June 26-July 1, 1966; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 17)
  - McFadden / IL [1/2], 1999; Series 7 (Box 220, Folder 12)
  - McFadden / IL [2/2], 1999; Series 7 (Box 220, Folder 13)
  - McGinnis, James #17648 and #16756, Undated; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 1)
  - National Conference on Education Packet, 1997-1998; Series 7 (Box 305, Folder 11)
  - National Conference on Education Program & Exposition, 1995; Series 7 (Box 265, Folder 1)
  - National Conference on Education Program & Exposition, 1996; Series 7 (Box 265, Folder 2)
  - National Conference on Education Program & Exposition, 1997; Series 7 (Box 265, Folder 3)
  - National Conference on Education Program & Exposition, 1998; Series 7 (Box 265, Folder 4)
  - National Conference on Education Program & Exposition, 1999; Series 7 (Box 265, Folder 5)
  - National Conference on Education Program & Exposition, 2000; Series 7 (Box 265, Folder 6)
  - National Conference on Education Program & Exposition, 2001; Series 7 (Box 266, Folder 1)
  - National Conference on Education Program & Exposition, 2002; Series 7 (Box 266, Folder 2)
  - National Study of the American School Superintendency, 1980; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 2)
  - Never Date the Boss, Undated; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 3)
  - New York City. Calvin E. Gross accepts award to AASA from National Tuberculosis Association, May 24, 1964; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 18)
  - New York City. Meeting of AASA Commission on Imperatives in Education, September 9-11, 1964; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 19)
  - New York City, Meeting of AASA Commission on School Buildings, March 18-20, 1965; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 20)
  - Norman, Oklahoma, Meeting of AASA Committee for the Advancement of School Administration, January 9-11, 1965; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 21)
  - North Conway, New Hampshire, AASA Northern New England Drive-In Conference of Community School Administrators, April 7-9, 1965; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 22)
  - North Conway, New Hampshire. Northern New England Drive-In Conference, April 13-15, 1966; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 41)
  - Preparing Schools and School Systems for the 21st Century, 1998; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 4)
  - Presentation Slides, 1990-1991; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 5)
  - Publications / AV Unit Cost, 1986-1992; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 6)
  - Publications on Microfiche 106 Ways Parents Can Help Students Achive, 1999; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 7)
  - Publications on Microfiche Articles of Faith and Hope for Public Education, 1997; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 8)
  - Publications on Microfiche Career Crisis in the School Superintendency? The Result of a National Survey, 2000; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 9)
  - Publications on Microfiche Coming Clean about Organizational Change: Leadership in the Real World, 1997; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 10)
  - Publications on Microfiche Conflict Resolution: Learning to Get Along, 1995; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 11)
  - Publications on Microfiche Effective School District Management: A Self-Review Instrument and Guide, 1999; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 12)
  - Publications on Microfiche The Flat Tax: Implications for Financing Public Schools, 1996; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 13)
  - Publications on Microfiche Getting Your Child Ready for School, 1999; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 14)
  - Publications on Microfiche Helping Your Child with Homework, 1999; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 15)
  - Publications on Microfiche Lessons Learned Along the Way: Survival Tips for School Leaders, 1999; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 16)
  - Publications on Microfiche Paradigm Lost: Reclaiming America's Educational Future, 1998; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 17)
  - Publications on Microfiche Parents: Partners in Education, 1999; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 18)
  - Publications on Microfiche Preparing Schools and School Systems for the 21st Century, 1999; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 19)
  - Publications on Microfiche Private School Vouchers: What Are the Real Choices?, 1996; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 20)
  - Publications on Microfiche Skills for Sucessful 21st Century School Leaders: Standards for Peak Performers, 1998; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 21)
  - Publications on Microfiche Telling the Truth about America's Public Schools, 1996; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 22)
  - Publications on Microfiche Total Leaders: Applying the Best Future-Focused Change Strategies to Education, 1998; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 23)
  - Rural/Small Schools Conference, 1997-1999; Series 7 (Box 305, Folder 12)
  - Skills for Successful Leadership, Undated; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 24)
  - Skills in Organizational Management, Undated; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 25)
  - Skills in Policy and Governance, Undated; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 26)
  - Speaking and Writing Skills [1/5], 1995; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 27)
  - Speaking and Writing Skills [2/5], 1995; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 28)
  - Speaking and Writing Skills [3/5], 1995; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 29)
  - Speaking and Writing Skills [4/5], 1995; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 30)
  - Speaking and Writing Skills [5/5], 1995; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 31)
  - Steffy, Betty, Undated; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 32)
  - The Study of the American School Superintendency, 1992; Series 7 (Box 221, Folder 33)
  - T.V. Program - Channel 2, 1967; Series 7 (Box 266, Folder 3)
  - T.V. Program - Channel 2, 1970; Series 7 (Box 266, Folder 4)
  - T.V. Guide - Convention, 1964; Series 7 (Box 266, Folder 5)
  - T.V. Guide - Convention - Closed Circuit, 1962; Series 7 (Box 266, Folder 6)
  - T.V. Guide - Convention, Undated; Series 7 (Box 266, Folder 7)
  - T.V. Program - Channel 2, Undated; Series 7 (Box 266, Folder 8)
  - T.V. 2 - Convention, Undated; Series 7 (Box 266, Folder 9)
  - T.V. Program - Channel 2, Undated; Series 7 (Box 266, Folder 10)
  - T.V. Program, 1966; Series 7 (Box 266, Folder 11)
  - T.V. Program & Committees, 1976; Series 7 (Box 266, Folder 12)
  - T.V. Program, 1977; Series 7 (Box 266, Folder 13)
  - T.V. Program & Committees, 1978; Series 7 (Box 266, Folder 14)
  - T.V. Program & Committees, 1974; Series 7 (Box 266, Folder 15)
  - Television Channel 2, 1971; Series 7 (Box 266, Folder 16)
  - Television Channel 2, 1972; Series 7 (Box 266, Folder 17)
  - Television Program, 1973; Series 7 (Box 266, Folder 18)
  - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, AASA-Sponsored Meeting on Inservice Education for Representatives for Delaware, New Jersey, and Pennsylvania, March 21-23, 1965; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 23)
  - Salt Lake City, Utah. Rocky Mountain Drive-In Conference, November 4-6, 1964; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 24)
  - Washington, D.C. 1965 AASA Architectural Jury, November 9-11, 1964; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 25)
  - Washington, D.C. AASA Board of Tellers Counts Primary Ballots for AASA Officers, November 4, 1965; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 26)
  - Washington, D.C., AASA Board of Tellers Counts Primary Ballots for AASA Officers, November 9, 1966; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 27)
  - Washington, D.C. AASA Meeting of Representatives to Joint project on the Administration of Mathematics Programs, May 3, 1965; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 28)
  - Washington, D.C., AASA Science Seminar, October 24-26, 1965; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 29)
  - Washington, D.C., AASA-Sponsored Meeting on Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, May 13-14, 1965; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 30)
  - Washington, D.C., Counting Final Ballots for 1964-65 AASA Officers, January 2, 1964; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 31)
  - Washington, D.C., First meeting, AASA Ethics Committee, September 4-5, 1964; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 32)
  - Washington, D.C. Meeting of AASA Commission on Administration in Newly Reorganized School Districts, March 27-28, 1964; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 33)
  - Washington, D.C., Meeting of AASA Commission on Religion and the Schools, April 3-4, 1964; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 34)
  - Washington, D.C., Meeting of AASA Project on Federal Government in Education, September 14, 1964; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 35)
  - Washington, D.C., Meeting of AASA Resolutions Committee, October 9-10, 1964; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 36)
  - Washington, D.C., Science Seminar, October 1-3, 1964; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 37)
  - Washington, D.C., Science Seminar for School Administrators, October 2-4, 1966; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 38)
- Public Policy, 1983-1997; Series 8; 3 Linear Feet
  This series consists of material created or held by AASA to explain or promote their agenda in regards to public policy, as well as material from the AASA Committee on Federal Policy and Legislation. The documents are concerned primarily with education policy at the federal level, but one folder contains documents related to healthcare policy. The series includes numerous briefs of amicus curiae written by AASA.
  - The 1989-90 Term of the United States Supreme Court and Its Impact on Public Schools, 1990; Series 8 (Box 249, Folder 1)
  - AASA Model Public Employee Collective Bargaining Law, 1976; Series 8 (Box 280, Folder 10)
  - Amicus Brief Decision-Making Rubric, Undated; Series 8 (Box 249, Folder 10)
  - Amicus Brief Filing re: Unitary Guidelines in Desegregation Cases, May, 1990; Series 8 (Box 249, Folder 11)
  - [Amicus Brief Report], 1987; Series 8 (Box 249, Folder 12)
  - Asbestos, 1987-1993; Series 8 (Box 268, Folder 4)
  - Board of Education of Oklahoma City v. Dowell et al Amicus Curiae, October, 1989; Series 8 (Box 249, Folder 18)
  - Board of Education of Oklahoma City v. Dowell et al Amicus Curiae, May 16, 1990; Series 8 (Box 249, Folder 19)
  - Board of Education of Kiryas Joel v Grumet and Hawk, Amicus Curiae, October, 1993; Series 8 (Box 249, Folder 20)
  - Board of Education of Oklahoma City v Dowell et al, 1990-1991; Series 8 (Box 250, Folder 1)
  - Brothers, Dr. Joyce, 1989-1991; Series 8 (Box 268, Folder 5)
  - Brown et al v. Woodland Joint Unified School District Amicus Brief, October, 1992; Series 8 (Box 268, Folder 6)
  - Brown et al v. Woodland Joint Unified School District, Amicus Curiae, October 5, 1992; Series 8 (Box 268, Folder 7)
  - Brown et al v Woodland Joint Unified School District Amicus Curiae, October 5, 1992; Series 8 (Box 250, Folder 2)
  - Cedar Rapids Community School District v Garrett F., Brief for the Petitioner, October, 1997; Series 8 (Box 250, Folder 3)
  - Cedar Rapids Community School District v Garrett F. Joint Appendix, October, 1997; Series 8 (Box 250, Folder 4)
  - Child Labor, 1990-1993; Series 8 (Box 268, Folder 8)
  - Children's Trust, 1991-2000; Series 8 (Box 268, Folder 9)
  - Civil Rights, 1985-1991; Series 8 (Box 268, Folder 10)
  - The Cost of Reform: Fiscal Implications of "A Nation at Risk", November, 1983; Series 8 (Box 250, Folder 6)
  - Deming/Baldridge/[Management of] Quality, 1990; Series 8 (Box 268, Folder 11)
  - Duel IDEA - Discipline/Guns, 1997-2001; Series 8 (Box 268, Folder 12)
  - [Email & Fax Printouts from Davis Case], December 2 & 3, 1998; Series 8 (Box 251, Folder 5)
  - Equal Access: Interpretation and Implementation Guidelines, Undated; Series 8 (Box 251, Folder 7)
  - Equal Access, 1984-1986; Series 8 (Box 268, Folder 13)
  - Explanation of FY1996 Continuing Resolution Table, January 11, 1996; Series 8 (Box 251, Folder 8)
  - Federal Policy & Legislation Committee, 1996-1998; Series 8 (Box 251, Folder 9)
  - Federal Policy and Legislation Committee, 1998-2000; Series 8 (Box 251, Folder 10)
  - Federal Policy and the Public Schools, 1967; Series 8 (Box 280, Folder 11)
  - Federal Policy and the Public Schools: A Series of Nine Essays Focusing on Questions and Issues Around Which Policy Evolves, 1967; Series 8 (Box 314, Folder 3)
  - The Federal Role in Education as Defined by the Elementary and Secondary Education Act since 1965, Undated; Series 8 (Box 251, Folder 11)
  - The Good News Club, Andrea Fournier and Darlene Fournier v Milford Central School Amicus Brief, October, 2000; Series 8 (Box 251, Folder 12)
  - Handguns, 1992-1993; Series 8 (Box 268, Folder 14)
  - Handicapped - Medicaid, 1988-1995; Series 8 (Box 269, Folder 1)
  - Handicapped - Military, 1986; Series 8 (Box 269, Folder 2)
  - Handicapped - Preschool, 1991-1992; Series 8 (Box 269, Folder 3)
  - [Handwritten Notes], September 9, 1990; Series 8 (Box 251, Folder 13)
  - Hatch Amendment / Privacy, September, 1985; Series 8 (Box 269, Folder 4)
  - [Healthcare Information Packet], 1999; Series 8 (Box 251, Folder 14)
  - IDEA [Individuals with Disabilities Education Act], 1997-1999; Series 8 (Box 269, Folder 5)
  - Ingraham and Andrews v Dade County School Boards Amicus Curiae, October, 1975; Series 8 (Box 251, Folder 15)
  - The Impact of Tuition Tax Credits on Federal Per Pupil Expenditures in Public and Private Schools, November, 1983; Series 8 (Box 251, Folder 16)
  - January 1998 Meeting, December 1, 1997; Series 8 (Box 251, Folder 17)
  - Karcher et al v May et al, Amicus Curiae, October, 1986; Series 8 (Box 251, Folder 18)
  - Legislative Agenda, January 7, 1996; Series 8 (Box 251, Folder 19)
  - Legislative Agenda, 1997; Series 8 (Box 251, Folder 20)
  - Legislative Corps Packet, 1999; Series 8 (Box 252, Folder 1)
  - Legislative Corps Packet, January, 2000; Series 8 (Box 252, Folder 2)
  - Legislative Corps Roster, September 14, 1998; Series 8 (Box 252, Folder 10)
  - Letter of June 26, 1990, Series 8 (Box 252, Folder 3)
  - [Loose Papers], 1992; Series 8 (Box 252, Folder 4)
  - Medicaid Information [1/2], 2000; Series 8 (Box 252, Folder 5)
  - Medicaid Information [2/2], 2000; Series 8 (Box 252, Folder 6)
  - Mozert et al v. Hawkins County Public Schools Amicus Brief, January, 1987; Series 8 (Box 252, Folder 9)
  - Owasso Independent School District v Falvo Amicus Brief, October, 2001; Series 8 (Box 305, Folder 13)
  - People for the American Way Amicus Brief, July 31, 1986; Series 8 (Box 305, Folder 14)
  - Perspectives on Education in America, 1991-1992; Series 8 (Box 269, Folder 6)
  - Private School Vouchers: What Are the Real Choices, 1996; Series 8 (Box 305, Folder 15)
  - Race-Based Decision Making, February 7, 1991; Series 8 (Box 305, Folder 16)
  - re: Edwards v Aguillard, June 19, 1987; Series 8 (Box 305, Folder 17)
  - Realities of Intergovernmental Relations, July, 1964; Series 8 (Box 280, Folder 12)
  - Regulations - Too Many, 1989-1990; Series 8 (Box 269, Folder 7)
  - Response to Amicus Brief in support of Evans et al, 1987, 1993; Series 8 (Box 305, Folder 18)
  - Romer v Evans, Amicus Curiae, 1995; Series 8 (Box 305, Folder 19)
  - School Lunch - 1987 & 1991 Budget & H.R. 7, 1985-1994; Series 8 (Box 269, Folder 8)
  - Social Security - Medicare - Health Insurance for Dependents, 1986, 1990-1995; Series 8 (Box 269, Folder 9)
  - Sunnyside School District: Important Notes per Sharon Lehnert Reddick Medicaid Management, 1997-1998; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 39)
  - Sunnyside School District - Medicaid Referrals and Resources, 1998-1999; Series 7 (Box 311, Folder 40)
  - Tax - Bonding "Arbitrage", 1986-1991; Series 8 (Box 269, Folder 10)
  - Textbook Suits, 1986; Series 8 (Box 269, Folder 11)
  - Understanding P.L. 101-392 - A Manual for the New Vocational Education Amendments, October, 1990; Series 8 (Box 316, Folder 10)
  - United States v. Alfonso Lopez, Jr. Amicus Curiae, October, 1993; Series 8 (Box 312, Folder 1)
  - U.S. and Sharon Taxman v. Board of Education of the Township of Piscataway, September, 1994; Series 8 (Box 312, Folder 2)